Contact

sherrylo2002@hotmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/sherry-dunlay-msn-rn-a61b87b6 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Healthcare Management
Patient Safety
Healthcare

Certifications

BLS

Registered Nurse Compact License

Sherry Dunlay MSN, RN

Nurse Leader | CNO

Enid, Oklahoma

Summary

Chief Nursing Officer and VP with 15+ years experience leading Patient Care Services, Operations, Physician Relations and Customer Satisfaction. Strong focus on HCAHPS, high reliability scorecard, fiscal management/growth strategies and reducing turnover. I've led 600 FTEs across multiple hospital departments and utilize Lean Methodology to improve processes. Increased Patient Satisfaction from 17% to 90%. As a system Co-Chair for the development of a Practice Nurse Residency Program, I worked across 20+ hospitals. A highly visible Nurse Leader, I build relationships and trust among teams.

- Maintained Nursing Productivity at over 100% using several software systems.
- Achieved number 1 rating for State of Missouri for HCAHPS in 2010-2011.
- Increased HCAHPS from 28% to 76% in 9 months.
- Decreased First Year Nursing turnover to 7.89, the lowest in SSM Health System.
- System Co-Chair for the development of Transition to Practice Nurse Residency Program for SSM Health via ANCC guidelines for potential accreditation of program. Worked across 20+ hospitals involving New Graduates, HR, Operational Leaders and Education.

Experience

INTEGRIS Health
Vice President of Patient Care Services/CNO
2017 - Present (3 years)

Enid, Oklahoma

A 207 bed facility (includes a separate Children's Psychiatric facility and LTACH) associated with 9 Hospital Integrated Health Care System.

• Responsible for 600 FTE's including Inpatient Nursing, Psychiatric Services, ED, Surgical Services, Outpatient Infusion, Cardiopulmonary Services, Cath

Lab, Rural Health Clinics, Imaging Services, Pharmacy, Rehab Services, Home Health and Infection Prevention.

- Press Ganey Employee Voice Survey increased participation from 72% in February 2017 to 83% in October 2017. Increased Nursing Engagement from 3.77 in February 2017 to 3.96 in October 2017.
- Using Lean Methodology implemented pilot for formalized PAT process to decrease room turnover time and better prepare patients for day of surgery. Included use of physician standardized PAT order sets, use of technology for pharmacy to verify meds prior to patient surgery day and moving clinic to a more ambulatory area. Patients are now arriving 1 hour prior to surgery instead of 2 hours with success driving surgeon and patient satisfaction.
- Maintained productivity collectively for all Nursing departments at 103%.
- Decreased Nursing turnover from 18.11% YS17 to 15.05% annualized FY18.

SSM Health St. Louis Vice President of Patient Care Services/CNO 2014 - 2017 (3 years) Centralia, IL

A 120 bed facility associated with a 20 Hospital Integrated Health Care System.

- Responsible for 400+ FTE's including Inpatient Nursing, ED, Surgical Services, Infection Prevention, Nursing Informatics, Outpatient Infusion Clinic, Wound Care Clinics (cross campus), Cardiopulmonary Services, Cath Lab, Anesthesia and Hospital Based Physician Clinics.
- Obtained 98% nursing staff participation in 2015 Patient Safety Cultural Survey by AHRQ resulting in an official A for Patient Safety 2016.
- YTD ending 2015 Nursing Productivity index averaging 101%. Decreased use of sitter hours by 25% using sitter algorithm.
- First Year Turnover 2016 hospital overall 13% Nursing First Year Turnover 7.89% lowest in the SSM System.
- Clinical Chair for \$20M project to design and develop relocation of/ construction of Surgical Services Areas and renovation of Emergency Department making hospital more Ambulatory friendly.

Missouri Southern State University Assistant Professor Nursing 2013 - 2014 (1 year)

University BSN Program accepting 65 students annually.

- Taught clinical skills and nursing theory/didactic to students in lab. Lecture, long-term and acute care settings.
- Provided dedicated leadership in clinical areas specifically maternal child health, ambulatory nursing care, emergency department and critical care.
- Worked directly with students in and out of the classroom.
- Applied and supported the principles of collaboration, creativity in interaction, and critical thinking related to student experiences.
- Attended department and division meetings with specific focus on ACEN accreditation work.

Mercy McCune Brooks Regional Hospital 10 years

COO/CNO 2011 - 2013 (2 years) Carthage, MO

A 49 bed facility associated with a 31 Hospital Integrated Health Care System.

- Responsible for 250+ FTE's including Nursing, Infection Control, Employee Health, Nursing Informatics, Clinical Education, Clinical Nutrition, Outpatient Infusion Services, Geriatric Outpatient Psychiatric Program, Pharmacy, Laboratory, Rehab Services, Home Health, Imaging, Emergency Medical Services, Cardiopulmonary Services, Ambulatory Hospital Clinics, and all hospital based physician programs (Anesthesia, Hospitalist, and ED).
- Collaborated with Mercy Joplin post-tornado to quickly accommodate increased patient volumes to serve the Joplin/Carthage community. Increased average daily census by 50%, increased surgical volumes by 60% and emergency department visits by 30% within 30 days post tornado FY2012.
- Developed and maintained oversight of Hospital based Physician Programs to include Hospitalist, Anesthesiology, and Emergency Department 2011.
- Participated in Hospital Engagement Network project with Missouri Hospital Association to reduce readmissions. Initially at 23% decreased to 10%.
 Specific focus on CHF 2013.
- Provided oversight for recent growth of Clinics including addition of Orthopedics, Oncology, and General Surgery Providers. Other provider specialties included Neurology, Rheumatology, Cardiology and Pain totaling 13 Providers.

CNO 2003 - 2013 (10 years) Carthage, MO

- Responsible for 125+ FTE's including Medical Surgical, Emergency
 Department, Surgical Services, Intensive Care Unit, Obstetrical Services,
 Outpatient Infusion Clinic, Infection Control and Employee Health, Nursing
 Education, Nursing Informatics, Clinical Nutrition, Emergency Medical
 Services, Geriatric Outpatient Psychiatric Service and Patient Advocate.
- Increased patient satisfaction from 17% to 90% sustaining 90% since 2006 (Press Ganey).
- Transitioned Geriatric Inpatient Psychiatric Unit to Intensive Geriatric Outpatient Program increasing hospital operating performance by \$800K annually 2010.
- Responsible for opening of new Obstetrical Services Program 2008. Staffed with experienced RN's and scrub techs. Stocked and supplied new unit within budget including surgical C-section suite. 100+ deliveries first year of operation.
- Named Chief Compliance Officer in 2005 to manage McCune Brooks
 Corporate Compliance Program ensuring compliance specifically with MBH
 Corporate Integrity Agreement.

Integris Grove General Hospital Clinical Director 2001 - 2003 (2 years) Grove, OK

- Managed 25+ FTE's in Emergency Department and House Supervision.
 Responsibilities included: staffing and scheduling, managing budget, policy and procedure maintenance, staff education, monitoring performance improvement indicators and developing corrective action initiatives as indicated, and recruitment/retention.
- Clinical Lead for program development of Cardiovascular Services to include Cardiac Cath Lab. Joint venture between Integris Grove General Hospital and Cardiologists. Responsible for hiring staff and securing training from other system hospitals.
- Took part in Magnet Journey at system level as part of MSN project.

Education

Pittsburg State University BSN, Nusing

University of Missouri-Kansas City MSN, Nursing Administration